Bigger house. Badder baddies. Bigger and better laughs.
Home Alone 4 is a comedy, family, tv movie film directed by Rod Daniel.
Kevin McCallister's parents have split up.
Now living with his mom, he decides to spend Christmas with his dad at
the mansion of his father's rich girlfriend, Natalie.
Meanwhile robber Marv Merchants, one of the villains from the first two movies,
partners up with a new criminal named Vera to hit Natalie's mansion.
Kevin McCallister, played by Mike Weinberg.
Marv Merchants, played by French Stewart.
Vera, played by Missi Pyle.
Prescott, played by Erick Avari.
Molly, played by Barbara Babcock.
Peter McCallister, played by Jason Beghe.
Home Alone 4 (also known as Home Alone: Taking Back the House) is a 2002 American made-for-television Christmas family comedy film directed by Rod Daniel, which was produced by Fox Television
Studios and first aired on ABC on November 3, 2002, as the first episode of the forty-seventh season of The Wonderful World of Disney, followed by a DVD release on September 2, 2003.
A standalone sequel to Home Alone 3 (1997) and the fourth installment in the Home Alone franchise, the film stars French Stewart,
Erick Avari, Barbara Babcock, Jason Beghe, Clare Carey, Joanna Going, Missi Pyle, and Mike Weinberg as Kevin McCallister.
It follows Kevin spending his Christmas with his father and his new girlfriend as his old enemy Marv and his wife Vera
come up with a plan to kidnap a visiting prince with help from an inside person that Kevin least suspects.
The film is the first in the Home Alone franchise to
not receive a theatrical release.
Home Alone 4 is the first film without any contributions from John Hughes, the creator of the
Home Alone series; further, it does not include any of the original cast members.
Whereas Home Alone 3 featured a standalone plot and new characters, this film brings back several of the main characters from
the first two films, including Kevin McCallister; however, all of the roles are played by different actors.
It was the last film that Rod Daniel directed before his
subsequent retirement, and his death in 2016.
The film explores themes of fight, burglar, holiday, house, father.
The tone is lighthearted.